海切尔  海切尔  海切尔
Hatchet, Hatchet, Hatchet!
加油  公牛队  球迷们  大声点
Come on, Toros. Let's make some noise!
幸会  三河城的大明星
Nice to meet the pride of trois-rivieres.
我还留着你边锋时期的新秀卡
I still got your wings rookie card.
那东西用来干嘛
So what's that worth?
作为收藏品啊
It's a collector's item.
如今的制卡门槛可没那么低
They don't make them like you anymore.
想打架吗
So do you wanna go?
正有此意  放马过来
Square up. Good luck.
他连碰都没碰到你啊
He didn't get a hand on you?
真是没人能跟你比打架了
You're going to be a force in the show.
加油  公牛队
Come on, Toros!
找个队医来
Get a trainer over here!
满座观众  全场起立
Capacity crowd is on its feet.
比赛还剩五秒结束
Five seconds on the clock.
这怎么可能  一个球员
How is it possible for one man
竟如此的技艺超群
to be blessed with so much skill?
我以前有个差不多的
I had one just like this,
不过是棕熊对蒙特利尔加拿大人
except it was Bruins and the Habs.
你从哪弄的
Where did you get it?
小儿肿瘤科某病童的生日礼物
Birthday present for someone in pediatric oncology.
22岁执行者  咯血
22-year-old enforcer with hemoptysis.
他是冰球运动员吗
He's a hockey player?
不  他是超级英雄
No, he's a superhero.
他咳嗽咳出血来
He's coughing up blood
可能是由于  他以体育名义打断别人肋骨
because he probably broke a rib and punctured a lung
致使别人肺部被刺破时
while breaking someone else's rib
自己也受伤  肋骨骨折并刺破肺
and puncturing their lung in the name of sport.
推断得挺好  不过18小时前
Nice conclusion to which the E.R. already jumped
已被急症室排除
18 hours ago.
短脚虾就是受气包
Short man equals bullied child.
我小时是平均身高  没受过欺负
I was average height as a kid and never bullied.
到现在为止了
Until now.
胸片已排除创伤后遗症
X-ray ruled out traumatic sequelae,
活动性肺结核和肺癌
overt TB, and lung cancer.
结节病  结节可能很小
Sarcoidosis. Nodules could be too small
胸片查不出来
to show up on an X-ray.
打架是冰球最精彩的部分
Fighting's the best part of hockey.
少了斗殴  等于看溜冰
Without it, you've got the Ice Capades.
打架与冰球毫不相干
Fighting has nothing to do with hockey.
不过似于篮球赛的拉拉队
It's like the cheerleaders at a basketball game.
拉拉队助阵是篮球赛最精彩的部分
Cheerleading's the best part of basketball.
少了拉拉队  等于看  篮球
Without it you've got... basketball.
他是鸭猎人
He's a duck hunter.
可能经接触飞禽
He could've contracted psittacosis
而染上鹦鹉热
from exposure to fowl.
他两周前曾被打落三颗牙
He had three teeth knocked out two weeks ago.
可能为感染导致的口腔出血
Infection could've led to oral bleeding.
他并没有持续性牙齿疼痛
Not without continuing dental pain.
那就是他下消化道受创
Then he took an elbow to the gut,
导致食管撕裂
which caused an esophageal tear.
奇斯  给病人做CT查结节病
Chase, CT the patient. Check for sarcoid.
亚当斯  做痰培养
Adams, sputum cultures
和鹦鹉热的血清学检查  陶博
and serologies for psittacosis. Taub...
我挺想给你解释
I'd tell you why I think your theory
你理论的错谬与荒唐之处
is not just wrong but ill-conceived,
但让你化验粪便  看是否有血液
but it's more fun to prove it
而自己得出结论  那更有意思
by having you check the stool for blood.
在等粑粑仙子到来时
And while we wait for the stool fairy,
我这正好缺人  不如来场冰球
I'm a man down, so you want to drop your pants
让我虐一把
and hit the ice.
你们能越快治愈我越好
The faster you guys can do this, the better.
国家冰球联盟正蠢蠢欲动
The NHL's been sniffing around,
住院对我职业前景没什么好处
and being in the hospital is not really helping my marketability.
你应该相当抢手吧
You have to be pretty good to get called up.
大概吧  害球队在我受罚期以少打多
Yeah, leading the league in penalty minutes.
还是急症室常客  更别提你伤的人
And visits to the E.R., not counting the ones you've caused.
我猜你不是冰球球迷
Not a hockey fan, I gather?
我是  这才是问题
I am. That's the point.
打架让体育竞技变得粗俗
Fighting cheapens a great sport.
拜托  那就好比说  传球让足球变得粗俗
Oh, come on, that's like saying passing cheapens football.
那是比赛的一部分
It's part of the game.
伤人的不是我
I don't cause injuries.
难道他们自伤吗
They're self-inflicted?
不  我防止伤害发生
No, I prevent them.
他们冲我来
I take the hit
小个子才能免于其难
so the smaller guys don't have to.
我以为你这样的会懂
I thought you'd appreciate that.
又是邻居家的小孩
Neighbor's baby again?
两个枕头  耳塞  三片安眠药
I could hear it through earplugs, two pillows,
依旧被吵得没法睡
and three sleeping pills.
你又想说什么
What is wrong with you?
我只说了  "嗯"
I just said, "Hmm."
我好几晚没睡好
You're trying to figure out
你却在探究
some deeper significance to my having
其中深意
a couple of crappy nights.
是谁在对一个"嗯"刨根究底
Which one of us is analyzing the word "Hmm" here?
好吧  我的错
Fine. Sorry.
接受你的道歉
Apology accepted.
话说回来
However...
不是孩子哭闹吵得你没法睡
it's not the crying that's keeping you awake.
黏人小孩的哭闹
The sound of a needy child
让你父爱荡漾
is stirring your paternal juices.
黏人小孩的哭闹
The sound of a needy child
高达112分贝  让我想杀人
at 112 decibels has stirred my inner murderer.
别惹我
Don't mess with me.
解释了你衬衫上的污渍
Explain the stains on your shirt.
你在泌乳
You're lactating.
你是家里的一脉单传  这个事实
The fact that you're the only fruit on your family tree
让你寝食难安
is getting to you.
这没什么大不了
It's not a big deal.
对  我可能永远当不了父亲
So I'll probably never be a dad.
是  很糟
It's-- it sucks.
我会因此辗转几夜  不过
I'll lose a little sleep, but--
你躲过一劫干嘛还要难过
You're not supposed to feel bad when you dodge a bullet.
像是幸存者心怀罪恶感
It's like you got survivor's guilt.
这世上确实有些事
There are actually things
比起肥皂剧和怪物卡车
in this world that give life even more meaning
能给生活带来更多意义
than soap operas and monster trucks.
而我们却错过了至少其一
And we happen to be missing out on at least one of them.
记得那个驯鹰人吗
Remember the falconer?
贝丝
Beth?
你还和其他驯鹰人约会过吗  当然是贝丝了
You dated two falconers? Yes, Beth.
你俩分手那晚
The night the two of you split up,
你来到我家
you came around to my place,
自怜自哀  借酒浇愁
wallowing in self-pity and tequila.
昏睡过去
You passed out.
那晚她打来电话  让我转告你
She called that night, asked me to give you a message.
她说她怀孕了
She said she was pregnant...
就是说  老天保佑  心诚则灵
which, God and planned parenthood willing,
你现在有个11岁大的孩子
means you are the father of an 11-year-old.
次日早上我告诉你
I told you the next morning...
以假设性口吻
Hypothetically.
问你要是她怀孕你怎么想
I asked you how you'd feel if Beth had gotten pregnant,
我引用你当时的话
and you said, and I quote,
"那会是我一辈子最大的错误"
"It would be the worst mistake of my life."
你演够了吧
And... scene.
别开国际玩笑了
Two performances sunday, dark mondays?
你自便吧
Just as well.
我想杀了我妈
I want to kill my mother.
我姥姥孤身一人
My popo's on her own,
我妈总让我去照顾她
and my mother always needs me to take care of her.
那你杀了你姥姥不就行了么
Well, you could kill popo instead.
我不得不带她逛街
I have to take her shopping,
访友  甚至去大西洋城
to her friends, to Atlantic city.
我爱她  但也不能每晚
I love her, but every night,
每个周末都要我照顾啊
every weekend...
如果有一个解决方法
And only if there was some solution,
比如一个你可以住的地方...
someplace where you could live...
肯定不是跟你父母住
That's not there.
我妈肯定不同意
My mom would freak.
那可是不敬不孝的表现
It would be the ultimate sign of disrespect.
好吧  那就忍着吧
Okay. Then stay.
或者你考虑下别再抱怨了
And maybe you consider not bitching about it?
可不是每个人都跟你一样幸运能这么独立
Not everyone's lucky enough to have your independence.
别担心
Don't worry.
当你没有家人的时候  你也会这么"幸运"了
When you lose your family, you'll have it too.
他没有结节病
He doesn't have sarcoid.
看啊
Look at that.
-那是他的脾脏  -我知道
- That's his spleen. - I know.
但他脾脏增大很明显
But he's gotten it supersized.
他多次受伤及手术 任何一次都可致
Deep vein thrombosis caused by any one of
深静脉血栓形成
his many injuries or surgeries.
白血病更能解释他的症状
Leukemia's a better fit.
咱们这病人基本上
We have a guy who is punishing
每天都要虐自己的身体
his body on a daily basis.
你难道不觉得这比癌症可能性更大吗
Don't you think that's a more likely cause than cancer?
不  因为她可没有成见
No, because she doesn't have an agenda.
这话说得可就不专业了啊
Well, that was incredibly unprofessional.
这其实都是陶博的错
Well, it was really Taub's fault.
如果不是你准备把她直接驳倒
If you're not prepared to slam her into the boards,
她可不会跟你作对
she's got no reason not to go after you.
我建议先用她的球衣蒙住她的头
Might I suggest pulling her jersey over her head first?
用超声检验深静脉血栓并查白细胞检验白血病
We should get an ultrasound for DVT and WBC for leukemia.
你认为我得了癌症吗
You think I could have cancer?
更有可能是深静脉血栓
More likely, it's just a DVT.
是我的经纪人  我得接这电话
This is my agent. I gotta get this, man.
说点好消息吧  肯尼
Give me some good news, Kenny.
我记得你说哪天都行
I thought you said any day.
好吧
Okay.
行
All right.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
我给贝丝打过电话了
I called Beth.
我有个11岁大的儿子
I have an 11-year-old son.
肝衰竭可改变激素水平
Liver failure could alter hormone levels,
导致乳腺异常发育
cause abnormal breast development.
酒精中毒
Alcoholism.
我们应该去检查他家和更衣室
We should search his home and locker room.
注意  那个要检查别人家的人
Note that the person who wants to search the home
昨晚没回家
didn't sleep in one last night.
你脸上有安全带勒过的痕迹
You have the imprint of a seatbelt buckle in your cheek.
我和我妈吵架了
I got in a fight with my mother.
她拿安全带打你了吗
She hit you with a seatbelt?
有可能是血色病
Could be hemochromatosis.
可解释肝脾病变
Explains the liver and the spleen,
但不能解释咯血
but hemoptysis is a stretch.
会不会是钩体病
What about leptospirosis?
有道理
That's a good fit,
但你忘了他可是一个职业运动员
if you ignore the fact that he's a pro athlete
跟绿巨人一样健硕
who looks like the Incredible Hulk,
意味着他可能长期应用激素
which means he's gotta be on steroids,
这更有道理一点
which is a better fit.
我们一定要把他生病的原因
All we really know for sure is it was his evil job
归结到他邪恶的工作
that caused the problems.
没错  我不喜欢他
Yes, I don't like him.
但并不意味着我的判断力会受影响
Doesn't mean my judgment's affected.
可能吧  咱们看一段回放录像
Maybe. Let's take a look at the instant replay.
就是这个动作引起了
This is the hit that precipitated
后面的斗殴事件
Bobby Orr's fight.
这动作有没有犯规
Dirty or clean?
没有犯规
The hit was clean.
真的吗
Really?
那家伙至少在被撞
The guy released the puck
一秒前就把球传了出去
at least a second before the hit.
我们只是意见相左  仅此而已
We have a difference of opinion. That's all.
绝对的
Absolutely.
也许她跟你一样充满偏见
Maybe she's as biased as you,
或者整个联赛都是这样
or maybe the entire league is.
在看过录像后  联赛纪律委员
After review, the league disciplinary commissioner
认定这个动作是犯规而且危险的
ruled the hit illegal and dangerous
罚那个球员停赛三场
and suspended the player for three games.
亚当斯和陶博去做钩体病的抗体检测
Adams and Taub, run antibody titers for lepto.
奇斯和朴  去他家
Chase and Park, check out the home,
还有更衣室看看有没有酒  激素
the locker room for booze, steroids,
和陶博的客观性
and Taub's objectivity.
至少你现在自由了
At least you're free.
你会自己租房子吗
Going to get your own place?
也得我能找到我租得起的房子
If I can find a place I can afford,
所以...就不了
so...no.
如果你愿意
If you want,
你可以在我那凑合一段时间
you can crash at my place
我那有间卧室空着
in the spare bedroom.
那有点怪吧
That might be kind of weird.
我住公寓里  又不是地窖
I live in an apartment, not a dungeon.
孤男寡女共处一室  我...
It's just two single people, opposite sex. I--
你的卧室可以从里面反锁
Your bedroom door has a lock on the inside.
如果你更喜欢睡车里  随你好了
Hey, if you prefer your car, be my guest.
有更昔洛韦的处方
Scrip for ganciclovir.
如果他隔壁的有传单  他可能也有
If his neighbor has mono, could mean he has mono.
如果他患传单  可解释脾病变和咯血
If he has mono, explains his spleen and hemoptysis.
该病为EB病毒所致
And it's caused by epstein-barr virus,
这也解释了他的肝脏问题
which explains his liver.
我车的天窗漏水
And my moonroof leaks.
谢谢你
Thank you.
咱们为什么不假装你不是孩子的爸爸
Why don't we just assume that you're not the dad?
如果你不是孩子爸爸  那她肯定就是
Either you're the dad, or she cheated on you
跟你爸劈腿了
with your dad.
沙画
Oh! Sand art.
我以前可喜欢这个了
I used to love this.
他有点可怜  又不是弱智
He's bitter, not mentally handicapped.
谁知道贝丝是怎么跟他说起你的
Who knows what Beth told him about you?
最坏的情况  她可能说你是强奸犯
At worst, you're a rapist.
最好的情况  你还是个强奸犯
At best, you're a rapist.
她可能说我是阵亡的战争英雄
Maybe she said I was a dead war hero.
由一个疯子妈妈养大  还被爸爸抛弃
Raised by a lunatic mother and abandoned by his father.
我知道了  买松鼠手铐
Oh, I know! Squirrel handcuffs.
你说他应该需要这个玩意吧
You think he's gotten need any of those?
如果你想让我知道后什么反应都没有
If you really wanted me to do nothing with this information,
那你当初为什么告诉我
then why did you give it to me?
因为你想要个孩子
Because you were pining for a kid,
而且你也应该知道自己其实有个孩子
and you deserved to know that you already had one.
但你也就是想当爸爸  实际并没准备好
But your parental cravings are more theoretical than applied.
你更想要的是传宗接代
You want vicarious immortality
而不是你这一辈子的负担
more than you want a lifelong burden.
你认为这孩子就是个噩梦吗
You're assuming he's going to be a nightmare.
如果他是个好孩子呢
What if he's a good kid?
他是个孩子
He's a kid.
最好的情况就是他只是个噩梦
Best you can hope for is he's a nightmare.
豪斯  我不天真
House, I'm not naive.
我知道这事可能会变得很麻烦
I realize that this thing could go very badly,
但重要的是  我儿子想见我
but the point is my son wants to meet me.
而我也想见他
And I want to meet him.
你是姥姥吧
Popo, I presume.
我自己进来了
I let myself in.
这位是
Um, this is--
见过了
We've met.
不是说整件事旨在远离姥姥吗
I thought the whole point of this was to get away from Popo.
我爸得了个囊肿要移除
My dad's getting a cyst removed,
我妈带他去诊所了
and my mother had to take him to the clinic.
别担心  她一小时后就走
Don't worry. She'll be gone in an hour.
我不担心  因为这不是我的问题
I'm not worried, because it's not my issue.
她安静得出奇
She seems awfully quiet.
你真该看看她喝醉的样子
You haven't seen her drunk.
鲍比
Bobby?
我看见他蜷缩在角落里哭泣
I found him crying in the fetal position.
不算新症状
It's not a new symptom.
他哭是因为肝衰竭
He's crying because his liver failure
引起的激素紊乱
threw his hormones out of whack.
除了哭  他恢复得很好
Aside from the crying, he's actually recovering nicely.
除了在书局碰到的男人[暗杀者]
Aside from the guy in the book depository,
肯尼迪家族去达拉斯的旅程还好得很呢
the Kennedys had a lovely trip to Dallas.
对头部不断的冲击
Repetitive blows to the head
会导致慢性损伤性脑病
can cause Chronic Traumatic Encephalopathy,
症状包括攻击性行为和抑郁
symptoms of which are aggressive behavior and depression.
你的意思是他的攻击性行为
So your theory is that his aggressive behavior
造成了他的攻击性行为
caused his aggressive behavior.
他没有抑郁
He's not depressed.
他那是烦恼  因为他知道
He's just bummed because he knows
他是个无能无才的白痴  只要输一场
he's a talentless moron who's only one lost fight
就得去酒吧端盘子去
away from being a barista.
我知道这会让人郁闷一阵的
I understand that can get to a guy after a while.
如果他不打冰球  或许可以保住一命
If he quits being an enforcer, it could save his life.
你不想救他的命
You don't want to save his life.
你是想断送他的前程
You want to kill his career.
我搬去奇斯的公寓住了
I moved into Chase's apartment.
他知道了  他正盯着咱俩一样的咖啡杯
He knows. He was staring at our matching cups.
告诉过你我们不该住一起的
I told you we should split up.
我们没和对方上床
We're not having sex. With each other..
还没
Yet.
是的
Yes.
是什么是啊
Yes?
我只是想说没人能预见未来
I just mean no one knows the future right now,
所以我们也不知道是否...
so we don't really know--
唯一能确诊慢性创伤性脑病的
The only conclusive test
只有靠尸检了
for CTE is post-mortem.
但大脑核磁共振
But an MRI of his brain
可能查出大脑白质不完整
could reveal white matter disintegrity,
也就是慢性创伤性脑病导致的症状
which is the effect of CTE.
为什么  你想睡她吗
Why? Are you trying to sleep with her?
更简单点  动动嘴皮子问一声就行
'cause the simpler technique is just to ask.
-我只是想做点好事  -不是
- I was doing something nice. - Mm, no.
不  这不对
Th--mm. No, that doesn't fit.
他十岁之后  只有过三次脑震荡
He's only had three concussions since he was ten.
不足以造成慢性创伤性脑病
It's not enough to cause CTE.
三次记录在案的脑震荡
Three reported concussions.
这些人从高中开始
These guys are taught in high school
就学会怎么在检测中蒙混过关了
how to dupe the tests.
内疚感
Guilt?
这太诋毁人了
This is really insulting.
这不是内疚感
It's not guilt.
朴克是朋友
Park is a friend.
就是内疚感
So it's guilt.
奇斯说服你离开你妈
Chase convinced you to leave mommy,
现在他觉得他该负责任
and now he feels responsible.
不做核磁共振  做个精神病学的评估
No MRI. Do a psych eval.
如果他不再哭了  就把他送回家
If he doesn't start weeping again, send him home.
威尔森医生
Dr. Wilson?
邓肯
Duncan.
叫我詹姆斯
Uh, James.
很高兴认识你
Uh, n-n-nice to meet you.
It's nice to meet you.
你好吗
How are you doing?
很好
Good.
好的
我给你买了这个
I got you this.
谢谢
Thank you.
拆吧
Go ahead.
好
Okay.
这里面有三个游戏
It's got three games built in,
但你可以从网站下载更多
but you can download more from the website.
是的  我知道
Yeah, I know.
你已经有一个了
You already have one.
多一个也没什么不好
I can always use a backup.
要给你们先上点喝的吗
Hi, can I start you with something to drink?
水就好了
Just water, please.
他送了你一个游戏机
You got a gamedeck?
当爹的不错啊
Way to go, dad.
精神病学的评估显示
According to your psych eval,
比你更欢乐的大概只有迪士尼乐园了
the only thing happier than you is Disneyland.
很抱歉昨晚让你看见那样的我
I'm sorry you had to see me like that last night.
我只是因为住院很难过
I'm just upset about being in the hospital and...
还得吃奇怪的药
I'm on some weird meds,
但它们应该起效了
but they must be working,
因为我现在好多了
because I'm feeling a lot better now.
抑郁可能是一些严重疾病的症状
Depression could be the symptom of a serious illness.
比如慢性创伤性脑病
CTE.
我姑姑把她能找到的相关文章都发我了
Yeah, my aunt sends me every article she can find on it.
你知道这是致命的
And you know it could kill you.
长期来说咯  很多东西都致命的
In the long run, like a lot of things.
你可能是对的
You might be right.
核磁共振能确诊
And an MRI could confirm that.
我的档案里已经有很多脑部创伤的记录了
I have enough evidence of head trauma in my file already, so...
我妈说你不擅长和正常人
My mom said you had trouble maintaining relationships
维持恋情
with normal people.
她还说你是个好人
She also said you were a nice guy.
我一直觉得她在说谎
I always figured she was lying
因为她不想让我痛恨自己有个游手好闲的爸爸
'cause she didn't want me to hate my deadbeat dad.
我当时不知道
I didn't know--
我知道
I-I know...
现在知道了
now.
-你是个聪明的孩子  -这得感谢你
- You're a bright kid. - Thanks to you.
感谢我妈  我也是一个心太软的胆小鬼
Thanks to my mom, I'm also a big, soft-hearted wuss.
我觉得你这点可能是遗传了咱们俩的吧
I think you may have gotten that from both of us.
我得走了  但是很高兴见到你
Uh, I gotta go, but it was really nice meeting you.
很高兴见到你  邓肯
It was nice meeting you, Duncan.
你想再一起出来吗
Uh, you want to hang out again?
当然
Absolutely.
今晚呢
Tonight?
今晚吗
我...有...
Well, I-I-- there's, um...
那就今晚吧
That would be great.
好的
Okay.
我会短信你
I'll text you.
谢谢  你怎么说服他做这个的
Thank you. How did you talk him into it?
我保证是匿名的  他就同意了
He agreed once I promised him anonymity.
张三夫妇明显喜欢李四这个名字
Mr. and Mrs. Doe liked the name John apparently.
不幸的是  我们只是浪费了他的时间
Unfortunately we just wasted his time
证明了豪斯是对的
and proved House right.
没有发现吗
Nothing?
那是什么
What about that?
是个伪影
That's an artifact.
那是个肿块
That's a density.
我知道你肯定觉得我是在自欺欺人
I know you think I'm convincing myself,
但是这家伙的脑袋瓜饱受摧残
But this brain has been hammered for years,
症状虽然难以捉摸  但是确实存在着
meaning evidence may be subtle, but it's there.
意味着你只看到自己想看到的东西
Meaning you see what you want to see.
当然  除非
Unless, of course,
奇斯是个傻冒  而我确实有脑损伤
Chase is an idiot, and I do have brain damage.
病人晕过去了
Patient's stroking out.
奇斯
Chase?
能把我弄出去吗
Can you get me out of--
有人不
Hello?
好消息是
The good news is,
只是孤立的眼肌麻痹
it's isolated ophthalmoplegia,
也就是说你没有中风
which means you didn't have a stroke.
坏消息是  陶博说对了
Bad news is, Taub was right.
你的病还没好
You're still sick.
我说的是"正确"而不是"全能"
I said "Right," not "Competent."
别再做慢性创伤性脑病的梦了
Bursts your CTE bubble.
你需要套全新的理论
You're going to need a whole new theory
才能让杰西叔和奥尔森姐妹消停会
to keep uncle Jesse and his Olsen twins on the bench.
我们能换个地方讨论我的无能吗
Can we discuss my incompetence somewhere else?
豪斯医生
Dr. House.
可以和你谈谈吗
Could I talk to you for a minute?
可能是神经梅毒
Could be neurosyphilis.
他才二十二岁
He's only 22.
但是他从十四岁就开始打冰球了
And he's been on the road since he was 14.
也就是说他早已饱受摧残了
So he was trash even before he was trash?
你难道不好奇他找我干什么吗
You curious about what he wanted?
我想他是希望我不再跟这个案子
I assume he wanted me off the case,
而你告诉他我小时候脑袋受过伤
and you told him I was hit in the head as a child,
你母亲让你保证会照顾好我
and your mother made you promise to take care of me.
他做着自己一直以来在做的事情
He was doing what he always does--
保护弱小[小个子]
sticking up for the little guy.
他让我向你道歉
He told me to apologize to you,
不然他就给我好看
or he would excrete down my throat.
我想他说的就是这个意思
I'm paraphrasing.
所以如果他问起你来  就说我绅士般地道歉了
So if he should ask, I was a gentleman,
不然我就给你好看
or I will excrete down your throat.
显微镜下多血管炎符合
Microscopic polyangiitis fits.
我们应该立即开始血浆置换治疗
We should start plasmapheresis immediately.
首先需要检测抗中性粒细胞胞质抗体确诊
We need to run an anca panel to confirm first.
血浆置换可能会致死
Putting him on plasmapheresis could make him bleed out.
显微镜下多血管炎恶化得很快
MPA can progress quickly.
在他的肺受到影响前
We may not have time
我们没多少时间了
before it reaches his lungs.
我觉得你说的没错
I think you're right.
与我的客观判断一致
Thus confirming my objectivity.
开始治疗吧
Start the treatment.
一团糟吧
Miserable yet?
他有礼貌  态度端正  是个全优生
He's polite, well-adjusted, and a straight-A student.
也就是说他根本不需要你
Which means he doesn't need you.
那你为什么不趁着蝴蝶效应还未成型
So why don't you get out while the butterfly effect
就脱身呢
is still in the cocoon stage?
我要给他做晚饭
I'm making him dinner.
谁还会给十一岁的孩子做晚饭呢
You don't make an 11-year-old dinner.
给他罐花生酱就好了
You give him a jar of peanut butter.
没问题的
It'll be fine.
我给他做道藜沙拉
I could give this kid a quinoa salad,
出于礼貌  他会吃的
and he would eat it just to be nice.
因为他和他老爸一样
'cause he's a gutless placater,
是个懦弱只会讨好人的人
just like his dad.
他人很好
He's nice.
这主意太糟糕了
This is a terrible idea.
因为我们喜欢彼此吗
Because we like each other?
没错
Yes.
是因为你说"我们喜欢彼此"
'cause of the statement "We like each other."
你们才认识二十五分钟
You've known him 25 minutes.
你对他的了解就是他骗你说他喜欢藜沙拉
All you know about him is that he'd lie about a quinoa salad,
都不知道那是什么玩意
whatever the hell that is.
你吃一个十一岁孩子的醋
You're jealous of an 11-year-old
因为你就像个十一岁的孩子那样不懂事
because you are an 11-year-old.
和我谈谈你吧
So tell me about yourself.
我知道你聪明
I mean, you're smart,
你人很好  那其他呢
you're nice, but what else?
我不知道  我还是个孩子
I don't know. I'm a kid.
没错
Right.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
没什么
Nothing.
你要花生酱吗
You want... peanut butter?
你有熏火腿吗
Do you have prosciutto?
你喜欢熏火腿
You like prosciutto?
-我很奇怪吧  -没有  没有
- I'm weird. - No, no.
我也喜欢
I-- I like it too.
我冰箱里有
I've got some in the fridge.
你有山羊奶酪吗
How about goat cheese?
我喜欢吃山羊奶酪
I love goat cheese.
这是我吃过的最好吃的批萨
I think that was the best pizza I ever had.
是第戎风味
It was the hint of Dijon.
你有阿姨叔叔伯伯或祖父母吗
Do you have any aunts or uncles or grandparents?
我妈妈莫名其妙和外祖父闹僵了
My mom got into some stupid fight with my grandfather.
他们就不和我们来往了
They all kind of cut us off.
你和你的父母有往来吗
Are you talking to your parents?
有的  他们看到你肯定会又惊又喜
Yes, and they're going to be very surprised and excited to meet you.
太棒啦
That's awesome.
你已经到达目的地
You have arrived at your destination.
那么
Well--
谢谢你的批萨
Thanks for the pizza.
好呀  好呀  今天...
Sure, sure. It was, uh--
我是说  很高兴和你一起吃晚餐
I mean, it was great to spend time with you and--
我爱你  爸爸
I love you, dad.
当名冰球运动员肯定不容易吧
Can't be easy doing what you do.
我的意思是  你喜欢你的职业吗
I mean, do you love it?
有意思吗
Is it fun?
我以前有间整形诊所
I had my own plastic surgery practice
很赚钱
making lots of money,
但是我不开心
but I wasn't happy.
我上医学院不是为了给人整形的
It wasn't what I went to med school for.
每年冬天我父亲都会在后院做个冰场
Every winter my dad would flood the backyard and made a rink.
我扮演拉缪
I was Lemieux.
我弟弟扮演格雷茨基
My little brother was Gretzky.
我比赛打得很好
I was good.
我连续三年获得北部冰球协会的
I won the NDHA scoring title
最佳得分选手称号
three years in a row.
我不断地长壮
I kept getting bigger
变得更强壮  打得更好
and stronger and better...
直到后来我水平下降了
till I didn't.
初级教练告诉我
My juniors coach told me that,
如果我还想留在冰球队
if I wanted to stay on the team,
那我就必须利用我的体格
then I'd have to use my size.
每次比赛  我上场打球的时间越来越少
Every game, I got less and less ice time
到现在我上场只为了打架
until it was all fighting
而不是打球
and no hockey.
我
I, uh...
我的胳膊觉得不太对劲
There's something going on with my arms.
我的手臂没有知觉了  我
I can't feel them. I--
医生  我感觉不到我的手臂
Doctor, I can't feel my arms.
病人手臂麻痹了
Patient's arms are now paralyzed.
抗中性粒细胞胞质抗体呈阴性
Anca panel was negative.
显微镜下小血管炎
It's not MPA.
莱姆氏病会导致麻痹
Lyme disease could cause paralysis.
如果他打猎的话  有可能会接触到蜱
If he was hunting, he'd be exposed to ticks.
没有出现红疹和心脏方面的问题
No target rash or cardiac involvement.
同屋室友让你晚上不得休息了吗
Roomies with benefits keeping you up?
是纸牌
Cribbage.
和朴克的姥姥一起玩
Played with Park's Popo.
是两个独立事件吗
Is that two separate events?
是她祖母
Grandmother.
肌萎缩性侧索硬化症可以解释那些症状
ALS could explain the symptoms.
涉及感觉可以排除肌萎缩性侧索硬化症
Sensory involvement rules out ALS.
好吧  这实在很有趣
Okay, yeah. This is interesting.
我们一会再回来研究病人
We'll get back to the patient in a second.
你的问题同威尔森一样除了...
Your issue is the same as Wilson's, except...
你是被那些不检点的女人所惑
You're haunted by the pitter-patter of tiny skanks.
你并非因害朴克
You don't feel guilty
被赶出家门而愧疚
about getting Park thrown out of her home.
你是为那些被你毁了的女人而内疚
You feel guilty about all the women that you've screwed over.
我妈正好需要1000块换雪胎
My mother needs 1,000 bucks for snow tires.
朴克是我的朋友  姥姥很有趣
Park's a friend. Popo's fun.
瘫痪由脸转移到胳膊上
Paralysis has gone from his face to his arms,
意味着其正在向下移动
meaning it's descending, which is the hallmark
这是肉毒杆菌中毒的标志
of botulism.
那就是他吃的东西有问题  真没意思
So it was something he ate. How innocuous.
你现在属于矫枉过正
You've overcome your bias by reversing it.
唯一的问题是爱一个病人
The only problem is that being in love with a patient
和恨一个病人同样会武断
is just as judgmental as being in hate.
我没发现任何污染的...
We didn't find any contaminated--
没有被污染的食物  我不是傻瓜
No contaminated food. I'm not an idiot.
但如果不是来自消化系统而是注射呢
But what if it's not from ingesting but from injecting?
他的队医为他进行过难治性肌肉痉挛
He was treated for intractable muscle spasms
的治疗
by the team's trainers.
有时他们就用肉毒杆菌
Sometimes they use botox.
我们需要用抗毒素...
We need to start the antitoxin--
抗毒素可能导致过敏
The antitoxin could cause anaphylaxis.
我们应该先进行测试确认
We need to test first to confirm.
为了证明我的观点  上次你说过
As if to prove my point, last time you said
在进行更危险的治疗前  没时间做测试了
there wasn't enough time to test prior to a more dangerous treatment.
情况不同
It's a different situation,
不同的症状  不同的诊断
different symptom, different diagnosis.
不同的情感
Different emotion.
给他用抗毒素
Give him the antitoxin.
怎么样
Anything?
没有副作用
No adverse effects.
奇斯让我和他一起住
Chase let me move in with him
以便逃离我祖母
to get away from my grandmother.
可他实际上让我祖母也搬了进来
Then he practically let my grandmother
和我们一起住
move in with the both of us.
对我也太好了吧
He's being way more than nice.
那究竟是为什么
Then which answer is it?
奇斯对于说服你搬出来住感到内疚
Chase feels guilty for pushing you to move out?
他没有说服我
He didn't push me.
-那是为了那些女人  -他就喜欢那种女人
- Guilt about skanks? - He loves skanks.
不会是第三种理由的
It's not the other option.
也是有人喜欢我的
There are people that like me.
有人甚至想和我上床
People even want to sleep with me.
其中有些人还长得不错
Some of them are even good-looking.
有他那样帅吗
That good-looking?
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
你感觉到什么了吗
You're feeling something?
是的
Yeah.
我可以神神叨叨你害我等了11年的事
I could give you crap for making me wait 11 years,
不过相反我为你没让我
but instead I'm going to thank you
再等11年而感谢你
for not making me wait another 11.
每个小女孩都想要匹小马
Every little girl wants a pony
直到他们发现得跟在后面收拾
till they have to clean up after it.
你认为我会退缩
You think I'm going to quit on this?
面对一个11岁的小孩
On an 11-year-old?
你唯一没退缩过的关系
The only relationship you haven't quit on
就是我
has been with me.
一个贫困的刻薄的自我陶醉者
Hmm. A needy, truculent narcissist.
我认为这是完美的父母身份训练
I think it's been perfect training for parenthood.
这一点也不挨边
That's not even close.
这可是你的余生
This is the rest of your life.
你搞砸了也没办法逃避
You screw this up, you don't get to run away.
你会毁了你们两人的生活
You get to ruin both your lives.
这比你以前处过和毁过的任何关系
This is a bigger responsibility than any you've ever taken on
都责任重大
and screwed up.
我明白
I know.
这也是为什么我如此兴奋
That's why I'm so excited about it.
你真觉得现在的工作比每天看着乳房要愉快吗
You're really happier doing this than looking at boobs all day?
还好我总会接触到你这样的病人
Luckily I get patients like you every now and again
能让我再次感受以前的快乐
who let me reexperience the joy.
你知道我一天最好的时光就是
You know, the best part of my day is when I'm sitting
打完别人坐在惩罚屋里
in that penalty box after I beat someone up.
那是我唯一感到安全的时刻
That's the only time I know I'm safe.
你觉得拉缪有过这种体会吗
Think Lemieux ever felt that way?
我不会回去了
I'm not going back.
冰球吗
To hockey?
是被迫去做什么...
To enforcing...
无论付出什么代价
whatever that costs.
那对你很好
Good for you.
第一个火箭射门得分
First goal for the pocket rocket.
鲍比
Bobby?
这里需要救护人员
We need a team in here!
他完全瘫痪了
He's completely paralyzed,
而且肉毒杆菌毒素检测为阴性
and he tested negative for botulism.
我现在接受孤注一掷的诊断了
I am now accepting long shots.
脊髓灰质炎
Polio.
有些孩子从来没接种过疫苗
Some kids were never vaccinated.
不会是这种一直从事体育运动
Unless they played sports all their lives
并且每年接受两次体检的人
and had two physicals a year.
会不会是异染性脑白质营养不良
How about MLD?
更不符合
That's a bad fit.
我这么说并非因为
I say that not because
异染性脑白质营养不良无法治疗
there's no treatment for MLD
而是确实不符合症状
But because it's a bad fit.
他的认知能力没有受到影响
His cognitive abilities are unaffected.
朊病毒病可以解释症状的周期性变化
Prion disease could explain the waxing and waning symptoms.
对于阮病毒病的检测是通过脑组织活体检查
The test for prions is a brain biopsy.
根据他的病史  肯定会发生脑肿胀
Given his history, there's got to be brain swelling.
我们不能冒险钻进他的颅骨里去
We can't risk drilling into his skull.
我们当然可以
Pretty sure we can.
我们也可以一直讨论下去直到
We also could keep talking until we can find
找到一个大家都同意的答案
an answer we all can agree on.
大家都同意吗
All of us?
那些喜欢他的  恨他的
Those who love him, those who hate him,
对他或你不屑一顾的...
those who don't give a crap about him or you--
或者我可以自己去跟福曼讨论这个可能性
Or I could just discuss it on my own with Foreman.
-他不是你的朋友  -我明白
- He's not your friend. - I get it.
他是病人  我不是...
He's a patient. I'm not--
他从没支持过你
He never had your back.
他没要求我一定要向你道歉
He didn't insist that I apologize to you.
他要求你不再跟进
He asked me to take you off the case.
给他做脑组织活体检查
Biopsy his brain.
嘿  爸爸
Hey, dad.
不好意思我来晚了
Sorry I'm late.
和我妈吵了一架
Got in a fight with my mom.
她只考虑自己
She's such a tool.
我相信她是好意
I'm sure she means well.
她想在哥斯达黎加
She wants to open a reserve in Costa Rica
为食肉鸟建一个保护区
for rescued birds of prey.
她是说真的吗
But how serious is she?
我印象里她过去也常说...
From my recollection, she used to talk about doing a lot...
没错  可是她连周一的机票都买了
Yeah, but she bought plane tickets for Monday.
哥斯达黎加很美的
Well, Costa Rica is beautiful.
那里的学校应该也不错
And the schools are supposed to be great.
我才不去
Oh, I'm not going.
那是她的愚蠢梦想  又不是我的
It's her stupid dream, not mine.
那你打算怎么办
Then what will you do?
我想...我或许可以...
I-I thought maybe I could, uh...
我可以跟你住吗
Maybe I could stay with you?
你家离我学校才3英里
Uh, y-your place is only 3 miles away from my school.
我可以搭公交车上学
I could bus it every day.
我的衣服自己洗
And I do my own laundry.
房间也会很干净
I keep my room tidy.
邓肯  这...这个
Duncan, th-this--
太突然了
This is very sudden.
我知道
I know.
对不起
I'm sorry.
求你别让我去丛林
Please don't send me to the jungle.
如果你母亲同意  我这边没问题
If it's okay with your mother, it's okay with me.
我请求退出此病例的治疗
Take me off the case.
很显然我已经丧失了客观性
I've obviously completely lost my objectivity.
不但帮不上忙  立场都不够中立
I'm not helping, I'm not even neutral.
我同意
Agreed.
所以我是不是该禁止你参与我所有病例呢
So why shouldn't I take you off all my cases?
你说的对  我恨恶霸
Because you were right. I hate bullies.
可你为我工作
You work for me.
你不是恶霸
You're not a bully.
我很确定我就是呢  蠢材
Pretty sure I am, dickwad.
我见过的恶霸很多
I've known a lot of bullies--
有人因为我身材矮小讨厌我
People who didn't like me because I'm short,
有人因为我是犹太人讨厌我
People who didn't like me because I'm Jewish...
好啦  我知道
Yeah, I get it.
你惹人讨厌的理由数不胜数
There's a long list of reasons not to like you.
你讥讽旁人毫不留情  但并不是出于自我膨胀
You relentlessly mock, but it's not for self-aggrandizement.
而是因为感情靠边思想为先
It's because ideas are bigger than feelings.
至少我乐于相信是这样
At least that's what I choose to believe.
你的副作用就是令我不再对讽刺敏感
I also thought you had the side effect of desensitizing me.
希伯来小个子
You little Hebe.
我给你讲讲道理  你搞砸了
Here's some ideas for you. You screwed up.
你总是搞砸  你刚刚说的都对
You kept on screwing up. Everything you said is true,
可是
except...
回避不是办法
it doesn't mean you walk away.
你要学会不轻信任何事情
You just learn to trust nothing.
你以为你感受到的一切
Everything you think you feel,
你以为你知晓的一切
everything you think you know.
每条线索都要质疑
Question every call,
每条血管都摸清
play through every whistle.
我刚有个灵感
I just had a light bulb.
好像是
Maybe.
灵感总是可信的
You can trust light bulbs.
停
Stop.
不是阮病
It's not prions.
EB病毒感染造成了传染性单核细胞增多症
Epstein-Barr gave him Mono.
同时也造成了米勒-费雪综合征
It also gave him Miller Fisher Syndrome.
血浆除去法疗效很好
The plasmapheresis played through the whistle.
我们采用血浆除去法治疗显微镜下多血管
We gave it to him for MPA,
病情恶化后我们停止了血浆除去法
but when he got worse, we took him off.
病情好转时又以为是抗毒素起了作用
When he got better, we thought it was the antitoxin.
其实那是血浆除去法的延续效果
But it was actually the plasmapheresis still working.
我们用对了疗法  只是诊错了病
We had the right treatment, just the wrong diagnosis.
是我的比喻给出了答案
It was my metaphor that solved the case.
重新用血浆除去法治疗  他会好起来的
Put him back on plasmapheresis. He'll be fine.
救场及时
Nice save.
可是纵观全场你还是无药可救
Didn't quite make up for being a sieve the rest of the game.
又在操心前女友的孩子
Ex-girlfriend's baby again?
他母亲要搬去哥斯达黎加
His mother is moving to Costa rica.
他问可不可以和我住
He asked if he could move in with me.
我就答应了
And I said yes.
不过是六七年而已
Well, it's only six or seven years.
除非他上不了大学  不过这种情况
Unless he can't get into college, in which case,
问题也在你心高命薄
it's more a matter of your life expectancy.
我就答应了
I said yes,
尽管我心里知道  我还远没有准备好
knowing I'm not remotely ready for that,
而他也没有准备好与母亲分开
knowing he's not ready to be separated from his mother.
这完全不是一个成熟理性的成年人的行为
This isn't the act of a mature, rational adult.
我
I--
我做不来父亲  豪斯
I can't do this, House.
你是对的
You were right.
我有个主意
I have an idea...
可以让这个问题再不困扰你
that can make this entire problem go away.
好  我真的很想听你英明睿智的玩笑
Yes, I really want to hear
说我当初就不该要孩子
your clever late-term abortion joke.
你从前说的都是对的
You were right about everything.
这是生活  是真实的
This is life. It's real.
问题不会凭空消失
It doesn't just go away.
你说的都不对[那都不是真的]
None of that is true.
邓肯
Duncan.
其实我叫温德尔
Actually... Wendel.
一个L
One "L."
如果你生气了
If you're going to get pissy,
一定记得  这全是豪斯的主意
Remember, it was House's idea.
你是演员
You're an actor?
拍过五支广告  《我们的日子》常驻
Five commercials and a recurring on Days of Our Lives.
你后悔没有孩子  所以我给你找了一个
You were regretting not having kids, so I gave you one...
以使你抛却遗憾
Thereby rendering you regret-free.
这份厚礼无价
It's a priceless gift.
-出去  -也不是无价
- Get out. - Well, it's not priceless
因为他只收我最低价
'cause he charges sag minimum.
出去
Get out!
别太在意哦  老爸
Chillax, dad.
你会澳洲口音吗
Can you do an Australian accent?
我刚接了电话
I just got the call.
三年合同  两百一十万
Three-year deal. $2.1 million.
那个后院冰场假装自己是拉缪的孩子呢
What about the flooded backyard and pretending to be Lemieux?
所以我才签了
That's why I took it.
付出那么多走到今天
After all I did to get here,
残缺的梦想总强过一无所有
half a dream is better than nothing.
或许新教练能看到初级教练看不到的东西
Maybe my new coach will see what my juniors coach didn't.
那倒不错
That'd be nice.
我不会和你上床的
I'm not sleeping with you.
真遗憾
That's a shame.
都是为了婆婆吧
This is about popo.
她也不会和我上床是吧
She's not sleeping with me either, right?
你嫉妒我
You were jealous of me.
我的家人
My family.
或许你拥有太多  而我又太少
Maybe you've got too much, and I've got too little.
说不定我们会上床的
I might sleep with you after all.
跟我通话的女人是贝丝吗
The woman that I called-- that was really Beth?
在非死不可上找的
Found her on Facebook.
她收多少钱
How much did she charge?
不收费  她还恨着你呢
Nothing. She's still pissed at you.
培根递我
Pass the bacon.
你不是喜欢吃熏火腿吗
I thought you liked prosciutto.
没人爱吃熏火腿
Nobody likes prosciutto.